A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Director, Herbert Spencer Gasser, Biographical Material, Series 6 FA814
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Biographical material, 6; 22.2 Cubic Feet 45 boxes, 4 volumes, 2 packages.
  - Memorabilia (Box 2)
    - Medals (packed and labeled individually) (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - #7 Kober Medal. Awarded by the Association of American Physicians, for research in scientific medicine, 1954
      - #8 Nobel Prize in physiology and medicine, 1944
      - #9 Silver medal inscribed "Hommage Herbert Spencer Gasser" Université Libre de Bruxelles
    - Movie: 16mm B & W Reversal 117ft. Old, but good in metal case. Copy made for use. Appears to be of trip to Switzerland, but no date or information available. D.W. Bronk seems to be in film (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 2 bound volumes containing notes and drawings in anatomy, neurology, histology and physiology made by H.S. Gasser while in Medical School (Box 3)
    - Reprint listing (Box 3)
      - H.S. Gasser and Associates Record kept of number of copies on hand, 1911-1956
      - List of reprints received, 1956-1961
        Includes 1957 list of discards.
    - Certificate of Merit. Issued by the President of the U.S. for services in World War II, 1941-1945, 1948 (Box 4)
    - Sc. D. University of Wisconsin (certificate), 1941 (Box 4)
    - Nobel Prize Illuminated citation, 1944 (Box 5A)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Material requires special handling.
    - Sc. D. Columbia University rolled diploma, 1945 (Box 4)
    - Sc. D. Harvard University diploma, in a box, 1948 (Box 4)
    - Honorifique de Docteur Université de Paris, rolled certificate, 1953 (Box 4)
    - National Academy of Sciences, citation rolled, 1934 (Box 4)
    - American Philosophical Society, citation, 1937 (Box 4)
    - Sociedad Argentina de biologia (Asociación Médica Argentina) Honorary diploma with letter, 1941 (Box 4)
    - Asociación Médica Argentina Honorary diploma, 1942 (Box 4)
    - Societas Regia Edinensis, diploma, 1943 (Box 4)
    - Regalis Societatis Londini, diploma, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Regia Academia Scientiarum Suecica, diploma Foreign Member, 1946; 2 copies (Box 4)
    - Suomalainen Tiedeakatemia, Helsink, diploma, 1947 (Box 4)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Fellow, citation, 1948 (Box 4)
    - Hood, Université de Paris (Box 4A)
    - Hood, Université Libre Bruxelles (Box 4A)
    - Early diplomas of father, Herman Gasser Rolled together (Box 5)
      - U.S. Patent for removing paint, 1881
      - Wisconsin State Board of Pharmacy, 1882
      - M.D. Northwestern University, 1883
      - Chicago Medical College. House Surgeon of Mercy Hospital, 1883
      - Wisconsin Medical Society, 1895
      - State Normal School of Wisconsin, 1907
      - B.A. University of Wisconsin, 1910
      - M.A. University of Wisconsin, 1911
      - M.D. Johns Hopkins University Medical School, 1915
      - Phi Sigma Biological Society, 1927
    - 2 slide rules (Box 5)
    - Bulb from A3 Alconap Oven (section cutting service) [Used by Miss Gregg for 12 1/2 years; she claims that it may have been used for 40 years before that] (Box 5)
    - Ram's Head paperweight; signed with a cat (Box 5)
    - T-square, initialed H.G. (Box 5)
    - Box of addresses, used and maintained by H.S. Gasser (Box 4A)
    - Model constructed of nerve (Box 5)
      Used as illustration in JPG 38 (1955) 709-728. Reprint included from An. Ins. Farm. Esp. 5 (1956) 11-26.
    - Sc. D. University of Pennsylvania, 1936 (Box 5)
    - Legum Doctoris, Washington University, St. Louis, 1940 (Box 5)
    - Sc. D. University of Rochester, 1940 (Box 5)
    - Doctor of Laws, Johns Hopkins University, 1947 (Box 5)
    - Docteur Honoris Causa Université Libre de Bruxelles, 1949 (Box 5)
    - Sc. D. The Rockefeller University, 1959 (Box 5)
    - American Neurological Association (Associate Member), 1935 (Box 5)
  - Scrap Book Laboratory photographs (prints), 1935-1945 (Package 1)
    Scattered negative numbers between #25977-35985 No indication of completeness or purpose in selection.
  - Laboratory notes — photographs enlargements, (mounted and unmounted) (Package 2)
    - Cat peroneal (Package 2, Folder 1)
    - Vasties bunches inpsoas level (Package 2, Folder 2)
    - Cat: ventral root lower thoracic and lower lumbar (Package 2, Folder 3)
    - Sural nerve — block 2, ser 2 (Package 2, Folder 4)
    - Cat ventral root (Package 2, Folder 5)
    - Cranial 5th (Package 2, Folder 6)
    - Enlargements 12000 x by latex (Package 2, Folder 7)
    - Sural, lobster nerve, saphenous cat (Package 2, Folder 8)
  - Collected Reprints of Herbert S. Gasser, 3 volumes
    - I 1912-25; II 1926-35; III 1936-60 each with Table of Contents and paged consecutively
  - Gift Volume presented, 1953 May 1
    Title page as follows: Keen friend to all thought and endeavor in science Herbert Spencer Gasser Director of The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research.
    These papers are offered you with the gratitude of your fellow workers, The Members of The Institute May 1, 1953 "What is now proved was once only imagined... " William Blake.
    Psychiatric research, see p. 69-79.
  - Addresses, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Excerpts: Atheomastix by Bishop Martin Fotherby 2p, undated
    - Dedication of 1st Avenue Playground at 67th St. 1 page, 1935 October 14
    - Staff meeting: "Irritability of mammalian nerve in relation to activity" announcement and holograph outline, 1935 November 8; 3 pp. and announcement
    - Address at Princeton: "Types of nerve fibers mediating sensory messages", 1936 January 27; Typescript 2 pp. Holograph notes 3 pp.
    - American Physiological Society, Washington, DC, 1936 March 25-28
      "Potentials in mammalian fibers" typescript, incomplete, 2 copies of p. 1 "read by title" Grundfest and Gasser "Irritability of mammalian nerve after excitation. " Typescript 2 pp.
    - University of Pennsylvania, Eldridge Reeves Johnson Foundation Lectures: "Electrical signs of nervous activity" by Joseph Erlanger 4/1, 4/2, 4/3 and Herbert Gasser at conferring of honorary degree. Typescript of Introduction, 1936 March 31 1936 April 6-7; 17 pp.
      Includes program.
    - American Neurological Association. Discussion of R.W. Gerard's "Factors influencing brain potentials", 1936 June; Typescript 2 pp.; also 2 pp. typed by a reporting service
    - New York Neurological Society. Discussion of papers on the human electroencephalogram in health and in certain mental disorders..., 1936 December 2; Typescript 5 pp. [probably reported by recorder]
    - No title; no further information. Starts... "The neuron doctrine is an application of the cellular doctrine... ", 1937; Typescript 6 pp.
    - Sigma Xi, University of Rochester "Science and Ourselves", 1937 February 22; Typescript carbon copy 4 pp. and program
    - Impressions from the experiment of 3 April 1937, 1937 April 3; Typescript 2 pp.
    - American Physiological Society, Memphis. "Response of nerve to two trains of rhythmic stimuli", 1937 April 21; Typescript 2 pp.
    - Yale Medical Society, New Haven. "Nerve fibers", 1937 May 12; Typescript carbon copy 19 pp.
    - American Neurological Association, Atlantic City: Symposium on Electrical Studies of Fundamental Nervous Processes. A. "In Peripheral Nerve", 1937 June 3; Some pages typescript, some handwritten for a total of 17, but some pages have been edited and duplicated.
    - "Potential distribution in the saphenous and peroneal nerves of the cat" Outline of Film I and II no additional information, 1937 November 26
    - University of Wisconsin Medical School. History of Electrophysiology. In celebration of William Snow Miller 80th birthday, 1938 March 8; Typescript 27 pp.
    - RIMR in honor of Dr. Rufus Cole retirement, 1938 April 30; Typescript carbon copy 6 pp.
  - Addresses, 1939-1941 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Association of Research in Nervous and Mental Diseases. Discussion of work by Dr. Hallowell and Pauline A. Davis, 1939 February; Typescript carbon 2 pp.
    - Remarks on "Present-day trends in Neuro-Psych Research" by S.B. Wort?, 1939 March 17; Typescript 3 pp.
    - Address at Memorial Service in honor of Dr. Charles R. Stockard at Cornell University Medical College, 1939 April 11
      Typescript carbon copy 3 pp; notebook size pages (10); includes holograph draft.
    - American Physiological Society, Toronto. Synapse Symposium "Axons as samples of Nervous Tissue". Published in Journal of Neurophysiology 1939, 2, 361, 1939 April 29; Typescript carbon copy 4 pp.
    - "Dr. Charles Ruppert Stockard, 1879-1939" 6 pp. duplicated from Minutes of RIMR Board of Scientific Directors, 1939 June 10
    - Resolutions on Retirement of: Alexis Carrel; Karl Landsteiner; P.A.T. Levine; and W.J.V. Osterhout. From Minutes of Board of Scientific Directors, 1939 June 10
    - University of Minnesota Medical School. 50th anniversary. "Methods of analysis of nervous action". Published in Chemistry and Medicine edited by Maurice B. Visscher, 1939 October 13; Typescript carbon 21 pp.
    - Untitled [appears to be on irritability], 1939 October; Typescript carbon 11 pp.
    - "Dorsal root reflexes" Delivered at the 25th reunion of Class of 1915 of The Johns Hopkins Medical School, 1940 February 24; Typescript carbon 5 pp. corrected copy
    - "Comic corticology (Mine or the Cat's) no information as to where or when used. Handwritten in pencil 5 pp. also 5 typed pages with penciled note, 1940 June
    - "Scientists are persons", 1940 June; Penciled note "not used". Typescript carbon 4 pp.
    - Remarks at funeral service for P.A.T. Levene, 1940 September 9; Typescript carbon copy 2 pp.
    - "Referred pain" (on reading Lewis) [no further information], 1940 November; Typescript carbon copy 2 pp.
    - "The passage of neural impulses through the dorsal roots of the spinal cord" Staff Conference at RI, 1940 November 29; Typescript carbon copy 11 pp.
    - Introduction of Rebecca Lancefield as Harvey lecturer, 1941 June 15; Typescript carbon copy 2 pp.
    - Remarks at dinner to honor Dr. Eugene Dubois, 1941 October 9; 6 pp. Typescript carbon, 2 copies.
  - Addresses, 1942-1954 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "Pain-producing impulses in peripheral nerves" Association for Research in Nervous and Mental Disease. At Waldorf Astoria. Spoken version, 1942 December 18; Typescript 9 pp.
    - American Neurological Assoc. Discussion of papers by Paul Weiss "New methods of nerve splicing and nerve grafting, " John Z. Young "The process of regeneration of nerve and muscle after immediate and delayed suture", 1942?; 2 pp. Typescript
    - Press release at death of Leslie Tillotson Webster, 1943 July 12; Typescript carbon 2 pp.
    - 70th birthday celebration for Joseph Erlanger. Delivered in St. Louis, 1944 January 5; Typescript 2 pp.
    - Memorial Minute: Leslie Tillotson Webster, 1894-1943, 1944 January 14; 5 pp. typescript with holograph corrections.
    - Address written at time of anti-vivisection bill introduced in New York State Legislature but "never delivered", 1944; 12 pp. typescript; 2nd copy 11 pp.
      Includes note from T.M. Rivers and comments by Peyton Rous, [see Carlson, A.J. correspondence].
    - Minute: Walter Bradford Cannon, 1871-1945 4pp, 1946 January 18
    - "Protocol for a review of psychiatry" read at dedication of Scientific Research Laboratory at McLean Hospital. Typescript (original and carbon copy) 13 pp. Also galley proof from Psychiatric Research, Harvard University monograph in medicine and public health, 9, 1946 May 17
    - "Emil du Bois-Raymond (1818-1896)" typescript 5pp. also typescript carbon copy with penciled changes indicated by editors. Proof returned to Dr. Webb Haymaker, Armed Forces Institute of Pathology, Washington, DC by whom article originally requested, 1949
    - Address at death of Leornor Michaelis, 1949 October?; 4 pp. typescript
    - At Dedication of new Biophysics Laboratory at The Johns Hopkins University, 1950 October 17; Typescript carbon 7 pp.
    - For Corporation meeting, The Rockefeller Institute, at the retirement of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. as President of the Board of Trustees, 1950 October 27; 4 pp. typescript carbon with holograph corrections
    - "James Bumgardner Murphy, 1884-1950" Minutes of Board of Scientific Directors, 1951 January 20; Typescript 5 pp.
    - Madison Presentation. Conduction in unmedullated fibers of dorsal roots, 1954 September; 3 pp. typescript
  - Lectures, addresses (undated and unidentified) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - The beginning of nerve oscillography by Erlanger and Gasser, 1 p. typescript
    - Biographical sketch of Joseph Erlanger, 1 p. typescript
    - French lecture, 12 pp. typescript with holograph corresctions
    - The properties of unmedullated nerve fibers with afferent function also called Jackson lecture [Hughlings Jackson], 17 pp. typescript
    - Unmyelinated nerve fibers with afferent function, undated; 16 pp. typescript
    - Discussion following paper by Dr. B. Frankenhaeuser on Friday June 6, 12 pp. typescript
    - Notes on size-vol mss, 4 pp. holograph
    - "Unmedullated nerve fibers" short version of published paper 1954/55, used for "St. Louis Cajal centennial NAS", 4 pp. typescript
    - Notes, 1958 June 26; 15 pp. holograph
    - [drC unmedullated], 5 pp. typescript
    - "Cornell Address", 15 pp. typescript
    - "Caracas program abstract", 3 pp. typescript
    - [Unmedullated fibers of dorsal root origin] Possibly 1958 address at University of Hong Kong. See correspondence with David Barker, 12 pp. typescript; 2 pp. and 3 cards holograph
  - Annual reports Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research From the Gasser laboratory after retiring as Director of the Institute (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Staff Conference, 1953
    - Two parts (scientific and general), 1953-1954
    - Two parts (scientific and general), 1954-1955
    - 1955-1956
    - 1956-1957
    - 1958-1959 1957-1958 (lackin)
    - 1959-1960
    - Description for Catalog, 1959-1960
  - Sir Henry Dale Penciled notes 16 pp. article appeared in British Medical Journal (1) 1955 1359-1361 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "Olfactory nerve fibers" 44 pp 2nd carbon copy; figures and galley proof Journal General Physiology (39) 1956 473-496
  - Published manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "Unmedullated nerve fibers" Trab. Inst. Cajal Invest. Biol. 1954/55 (45) 1-8, 1954-1955
    - Acceptance of Kober Medal for 1954" Trans. Assoc. American Physicians (67) 1954 44-46 corrected, Typescript
    - "Chairman's Introductory Remarks" Muscular Dystrophy Association of America. Proceedings, 3rd Medical Conference, 1954, NY 143-144 also American Journal of Physical Medicine 35 (1955) 4pp typescript, editor's copy. [Does not appear in bibliography]
    - "Conduction in unmedullated fibers in dorsal roots" American Journal of Physiology, abstract 1954 (179) 637
    - "Alan Gregg, 1890-1957" Yearbook of the American Philosophical Society, 1957 126-129 7 pp. corrected manuscript
    - "Fibras nerviosus amielinicas con funcion aferents" An. Ins. Farm. Esp. 5 (1956) 11-26, 21 pp. typescript carbon copy
    - "Comparison of the structure, as revealed with the electron microscope, and the physiology of the unmedullated fibers in the skin nerves and in the olfactory nerves. Exp. Cell Research 5 (1958) 3-17, 19 pp. typescript carbon copy
  - Published manuscripts
    - "Effect of the method of leading on the recording of a fiber spectrum" Journal General Physiology 43 (1960) 927-940, 23 pp. typescript carbon copy (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Penciled notes for a publication which appears to be on the properties of mammalian nerve fibers (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Penciled notes for a publication which appears to be on dorsal root ganglia which includes graphs and drawings (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Laboratory notebooks: 11 notebooks of various groups of measurements from 1939 to 1960, 1939-1960 (Box 7)
    - 1-3-39 Saph I Cat I
    - 1939 Saph nerve #4 Rabbit #3
    - 5-16-38 Saph Nerve Cat fiber counts #4
    - 5-1948 Distribution of fibers by sizes
    - 4-1952 Analysis of sural electron microscope
    - 2/52-6/56 Measurements olfactory Schwann sheaths
    - 5-1960 Bundles ventral root, lower lumbar, lower thoracic
      Includes data from 1939.
    - 1960 Internodes and fiber sizes; also Hunt McIntyre data
    - 1960 Electron microscope notebook; starts with Dec. 1929 histology
    - 11/54-2/60 Electronmicroscope Photos Record 2 books
  - Laboratory notebooks: 9 notebooks of records procedures, explanations and analyses (Box 8)
    - 1938 September-1940 January
    - 1939 February-1947 February
    - 1947 February-1950 January
    - 1948 May-1954 April
    - 1950 January-1955 June
    - 1955 June-1956 September
    - 1956 September-1957 October
    - 1957 October-1959 June
    - Oscillograph Records, 1959 July-1961 March
    - Laboratory procedures on cards (in envelope)
    - Equipment information
  - Laboratory charges, 1952-1959; 7 folders (Box 9)
    Arranged by academic (fiscal) year.
  - Laboratory charges, 1959-1961; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Microfilm strips of sections or rhythms, 1937-1952 (Box 11)
    Individually packed in roll boxes, labeled and dated and arranged chronologically by year 2 (1937); 1 (1938); 1 (1939); 7 (1945) 1 (1949); 9 (1951); 22 (1952).
  - Microfilm strips of sections or rhythms 12 (1953); 37 (1954), 1953-1954 (Box 12)
  - Microfilm strips of sections or rhythms 27 (1955); 22 (1956), 1955-1956 (Box 13)
  - Microfilm strips of sections or rhythms 16 (1957); 11 (1958); 9 (1959); 4 (1960); 1 (1961), 1957-1961 (Box 14)
  - Laboratory notes — photographs (Box 15)
    This group of photographs of experimental work has been arranged chronologically by the number of the negative.
    21 in a folder are unnumbered #1060-#9768 incomplete.
  - Laboratory notes — photographs
    Figures used in publications are arranged by publication.
    - vol. 127 Am. Journal of Physiology pp. 393-414, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - vol. 33 Journal of General Physiology pp. 651-690, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - vol. 38. Journal of General Physiology pp. 705-728, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - vol. 39 Journal of General Physiology pp. 473-496, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - suppl. 5 Experimental Cell Research pp. 3-17, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - vol. 41 Journal of General Physiology pp. 613-632, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - vol. 43 Journal of General Physiology pp. 927-940, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Laboratory notes, drawings, calculations, photos (Box 17)
    - undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 1948 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1949 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 1952 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Calculations for Fig. 18 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Photographs of 0.258 u particles (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Photographs of fascicules ca 400 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Photos and calculations, 11 envelopes (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Cat saphenous, 1953
      - cat saphenous tetanus, 1955
      - Cat dorsal root, 1945
      - Mammalian recovery curves, 1957
      - Diphasic saphenous, 1957
      - varied stimulus effects, 1954
    - Notes, drawings and graphs, 1948 1952 1954; 6 envelopes (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Saphenous II, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - 4 envelopes including (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - 5th nerve
      - Phrenic
      - Mammalian recovery curve spectra, 1956-1958
    - Cartoon drawing Fig. 1 and Fig. 21 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      Relating to Lorente de No but no further information.
  - Laboratory notes - photographs
    - Dorsal roo, cat, frog, C fibers, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Frog nerve, 1945 1949 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Cat Saphenous Delta and R includes 1938 notes, 1948-1949 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Dog, monkey, cat saphenous, 1947-1950 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Sural, 1948-1949 1957-1958 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Cat skin, 1952 1953-1957 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Pike, pig, cat olfactory, 1953-1955 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Cat cranial cdr V, 1955 November 30 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Bull frog splanchnic; cat saphenous and hypogastric, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Pipiens; heat in xylocaine, 1959 January 30 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Laboratory notes — photographs
    Mostly mounted and with individual, descriptions.
    Arranged in subject groupings.
    - Cat saphenous, 1944-1945 1947 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Cat saphenous, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Cat saphenous, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Cat saphenous action potential 1954-59 of 1948 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Cat saphenous, 1958-1959 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Prints of conduction, 1957-1958 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Saphenous tangent integrals, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Saphenous, sural. Block approach (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Laboratory photographs; prints of microphotos: Groups of pictures taken during experimental procedures. Each picture individually labeled
    - Ag stain analyzed 1948 saphenous fascic. I field 1-2 2 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Ag stain analyzed: Ranson nerve; May 10 fascic. II (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Comparative fixation and embedding (Box 20A, Folder 3)
      - 1950 January 30 1951 December 29 1951 December 31
      - Altmann 1st block; Block 2, 1952 January 9 1952 January 23 1952 January 30
      - Krebs formalin; Krebs osmium meth A; Colloidin paraffin; celpar, 1952 February 6
      - Kos 5% CH₃ and 20% CH₃, 1952 March 26
    - R.I. II; Saphenous C Schmitt; silver stain, 1951 (Box 20A, Folder 4)
    - Normal cat saphenous 4; formalin; osmic vapor, 1951 (Box 20A, Folder 5)
    - 2/1; 2/15; 3/23 3C saphenous to end point controls 1-23; 24-28, 1951 (Box 20B, Folder 6)
    - Saphenous 2pp not spread at 45° os vapor; unbuffered osmic, 1951 November (Box 20B, Folder 7)
    - C fiber Palade nearness to bifurcation, 1951-1954 (Box 20B, Folder 8)
    - Comparison size. Paraffin and plastic. Kos sural. Cross section of dorsal root node, 1952 February-April (Box 20B, Folder 9)
  - Laboratory photographs; prints of microphotos (Box 21)
    - Degenerative saphenous, 1951 May (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Hypogastric; controls and ganglia, 1951 May-June (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Splenic, 1951 May (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Hypogastric, 1952 October (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Dorsal root Kos extra prints, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - C fiber sural Kos extra prints, 1952 April (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - I.R.T. Sural Kos 39° II and IIa control, 1952 April (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Medullated long sections Ia Saphenous various magnifications, 1952 March (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Dorsal root Kos 20% CH₃; b.p. overnight 3 cross sections of nodes, of small fibers "not very good", 1952 February (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Dorsal root close to cord; 6-7mm. from cord; in and near ganglia opp. cells; 2 middle long, 1952 June-October (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Oct. Lissauer sections cord traverse (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Hunt ganglion sections arranged at levels beginning at the root and all levels contained ganglion cells except 7-1. 7-1 extremely close to ganglion (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Laboratory photographs; prints of microphotos (Box 22)
    - Dorsal root ganglia 1 and 2, 1952 December (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Dorsal root ganlia 3, 1952 December (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - auto. horn Kos, 1953 January (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous and chick sciatic M.A. Jakers; Betty Geren, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Pig olfactory mucosa m. P6, P8, 1953 April (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Pig olfactory epithelium, 1953 December (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Medullated Cat accessory saph. Kos 6 hours, 1953 December (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Pig olfactory Pig8-l; Pig 3 Film 2dissected nerve; olfactory membrane Kos, 1953 April (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Olfactory lobe Pig 7 Kos; 10 day mouse Golgi olfactory glom, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Pig olfactory nerve P81L level 1-4, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)